# TUHIN SETHI

Software Developer (.NET core)

8178156566



tuhinsethiofficial@gmail.com



New Delhi,110063



### **SUMMARY**

I am a reliable full-stack .NET core developer with excellent coding, debugging and project management capabilities who accomplishes project goals consistently with scalable code. I am looking to join a team where I get challenged and I can learn and improve my already glowing skill-set .

I have a total experience of over 4 years working with .NET development and I am currently fetching 13L INR .

## **EDUCATION**

#### **IP University**

Bachelor's Degree in Technology (B.tech) 2016 – 2020 Grade - 7.6/10

#### **Ryan International School**

Higher Secondary education 2014-2016 Percentage - 80%

#### SKILLS

- Strong organizational and timemanagement skills
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail-oriented and able to handle multiple tasks simultaneously

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- SOL
- .NET development (core), ASP.NET
- MVC
- Razor pages
- · Agile and scrum methodology
- Entity framework
- Scripting Languages: jQuery, basic Angular and React.js
- Programming Languages : C# , java , basic python
- HTML /CSS designing capability
- Microservices

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Developer**

American Epay systems | 2021- present

- Worked as a Team-coach and a software developer
- I worked on an Employer solutions product where I built complex business logic and dynamic UI to suit the clients requirement . I had to make sure that logic was highly accurate and calculations were precise to compile with harsh US laws.
- Migrated the product to .NET 8 from ASP.NET and created a multi-platform application
- Converted a complex architecture into clean architecture over MVC using Razor pages
- Analyzed user needs and software requirements to determine design feasibility

#### Junior Software Developer

American Epay systems | 2020-2021

- Joined as a fresher and got exposure into working in a project from scratch
- Worked on creating , optimizing and operating database for already running architecture
- Handled production support , bug fixes and creation of new functionalities for the product
- Worked on optimization of queries, oversaw deployments and configurations of the product

#### Software Development Intern

Mekvahan | 2017

- · Assisted development over inhouse built product
- · Created robust, user friendly UI and worked over angular
- Learned development over java, php and Styling over HTML /CSS
- Learned how things work under product based startups